<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Site</title>
    <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>My Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>My Site</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/event/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/event/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Hugo Blox Builder&amp;rsquo;s 
 feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using 
.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including 
 such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Writing in the Digital Age</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/publication/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/publication/05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic writing remains a crucial instrument of scholarly communication, yet in the digital age its nature and capabilities have changed significantly. New technologies have opened access to vast sources of information, collaborative tools, and platforms for rapid dissemination of research results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transformation-of-academic-writing&#34;&gt;Transformation of Academic Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital tools enable researchers to work on texts in real time, ensuring collaborative editing and instant data exchange. Integration with version control systems guarantees transparency of changes and enhances the reproducibility of studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, academic writing is increasingly accompanied by data visualization, interactive elements, and links to open repositories. This strengthens the importance of interdisciplinary collaboration and makes research more accessible to a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-impact-of-open-science&#34;&gt;The Impact of Open Science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergence of the &lt;strong&gt;Open Science&lt;/strong&gt; paradigm has changed expectations for publications. Today, researchers are expected not only to present a text but also to provide open access to data, code, and methodologies. This fosters a new culture of academic writing, where transparency and accessibility become essential values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic writing in the digital age extends beyond traditional publications. It is becoming a multilayered process that integrates text, data, code, and visualization. Mastering new digital practices allows researchers to enhance the quality of communication and strengthen their position in the global academic community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight Markup Languages</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/publication/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/publication/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;lightweight-markup-languages&#34;&gt;Lightweight Markup Languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightweight markup languages have become a standard for preparing scientific and technical texts due to their simplicity and versatility. They allow structuring documents, adding links, tables, images, and formulas without the need for complex formats or specialized software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most widely used example is &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;, which is actively applied in academia, software development, and documentation. Its main advantage lies in the readability of the source text: even without rendering, the document remains understandable. This makes it a convenient tool both for drafting and for publishing materials online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other languages, such as &lt;strong&gt;reStructuredText&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;AsciiDoc&lt;/strong&gt;, provide extended capabilities for structuring information, making them especially useful in large projects and for preparing official documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of lightweight markup languages supports the unification of approaches to text processing, accelerates collaborative editing, and ensures integration with modern version control systems and publishing platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing a Work Report</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/publication/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/publication/03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-a-work-report&#34;&gt;Preparing a Work Report&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A work report is an important tool for documenting results, analyzing completed steps, and setting further objectives. Its structure depends on the purpose of the document and the context of its use, but some general principles remain consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction of the report outlines the goals and objectives that were to be achieved. This is followed by a description of the methodology: the approaches used, the tools applied, and the rationale for selecting specific methods. The main body of the report presents the results, where it is essential not only to list the facts but also to provide their analytical interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concluding section contains conclusions and recommendations. Here the effectiveness of the work is evaluated, and the prospects for further development of the project or research are identified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A well-prepared report contributes to knowledge systematization, increases transparency of activities, and serves as a foundation for management decisions or academic evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Programming Languages</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/publication/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/publication/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming is a field where programming languages serve as the foundation for process modeling, numerical calculations, and data analysis. The choice of a specific tool depends on requirements for accuracy, computational speed, and ease of integration with existing research infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-directions&#34;&gt;Main Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, one of the first and most significant languages for scientific computing was &lt;strong&gt;Fortran&lt;/strong&gt;, which is still applied in engineering calculations and physical modeling. Later, the &lt;strong&gt;MATLAB&lt;/strong&gt; environment gained wide popularity, providing researchers with tools for numerical modeling, signal processing, and data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 21st century, &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt; came to the forefront thanks to its rich ecosystem of libraries such as NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, and Matplotlib. It has become a universal language for data processing and reproducible research. Alongside it, &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt; is actively used, focusing on statistical analysis and widely applied in bioinformatics, sociology, and economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particular attention has been drawn to &lt;strong&gt;Julia&lt;/strong&gt;, a modern language that combines high-level syntax with strong performance. It has proven especially useful in computational mathematics and in developing models requiring intensive calculations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;applications-in-academia&#34;&gt;Applications in Academia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming languages cover a wide range of tasks: from modeling physical processes and engineering systems to analyzing large datasets in medicine, economics, and social sciences. They are also used in preparing scientific publications, building reproducible experiments, and integrating machine learning methods into research practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;selection-criteria&#34;&gt;Selection Criteria&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When choosing a language, factors such as computational performance, availability of libraries and specialized tools, ease of integration with existing systems, community activity, and documentation accessibility are taken into account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming languages have become a fundamental tool of modern science. Mastering them enables solving problems of varying complexity — from simple statistical calculations to supercomputer-scale modeling. Proficiency in such languages opens up new opportunities for students and researchers across different fields of knowledge and lays the foundation for the development of interdisciplinary projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Website with Hugo Academic</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/project/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/project/hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;academic-website-as-part-of-a-scholarly-career&#34;&gt;Academic Website as Part of a Scholarly Career&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern academic environment requires not only publications but also a well-structured digital presence. An academic website serves as a platform to compile a portfolio, organize materials, and present research and projects to a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most convenient tools for this purpose is &lt;strong&gt;Hugo Academic&lt;/strong&gt;. The platform combines ease of setup, flexibility in content management, and a wide range of options for publishing papers, showcasing projects, and integrating with external services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A website built on Hugo Academic makes it possible to present a list of publications, link profiles from academic databases, structure biographical information, and highlight research interests. Such a resource not only facilitates communication with colleagues and students but also becomes an essential element of academic branding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Hugo Academic opens the way to building a modern digital identity for a scholar, emphasizing openness, systematization, and integration with the international academic community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/post/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/post/05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekly-summary&#34;&gt;Weekly Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beginning of September was marked by active preparation for the new academic year. I organized my notes, reviewed study plans for upcoming subjects, and identified priority areas for development. My main focus was on the in-depth study of information systems, as they form the foundation of the Business Informatics program. In addition to academic activities, I took part in discussions of organizational matters with fellow students and began preparing for upcoming project assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version Control</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/publication/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/publication/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;version-control&#34;&gt;Version Control&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version control is a key component of modern software development. It ensures tracking of changes in source code, enables multiple developers to work on a project simultaneously, and guarantees the preservation of the product’s development history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version control systems such as &lt;strong&gt;Git&lt;/strong&gt; allow developers to create branches, merge changes, revert to previous code states, and maintain consistency in collaborative work. The use of distributed repositories makes the development process more flexible and resilient to errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond its technical functions, version control plays a crucial role in organizing teamwork. It promotes transparency, simplifies code review, and forms the foundation for implementing DevOps practices, including continuous integration and deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s rapidly evolving field of software engineering, proficiency in version control systems is not merely a useful skill but a fundamental standard of professional practice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/post/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/post/04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekly-summary&#34;&gt;Weekly Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week was dedicated to developing analytical thinking and working with economic indicators. I studied the basics of financial analysis and compared them with the principles of business informatics. To reinforce the material, I completed several practical exercises related to data interpretation and forecasting. In the evenings, I read foreign articles to improve my knowledge of English terminology in the field of information technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/post/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/post/03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekly-summary&#34;&gt;Weekly Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I devoted particular attention to the study of project management. I became familiar with the basic principles of Agile and examined how flexible methodologies are applied in modern business. My preparation included reading articles and analyzing practical examples of implementing digital tools in corporate environments. In addition, I started working on a small academic project that requires linking data analysis tasks with managerial decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/post/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/post/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekly-summary&#34;&gt;Weekly Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second week of August was dedicated to working with SQL. I practiced writing queries and analyzing small training datasets. This helped me better understand the connection between theoretical knowledge and its application in business analytics tasks. I also attended a lecture on the development of digital ecosystems, where the role of information systems integration in organizational management was discussed. In my free time, I continued sports activities and watched popular science materials.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Week</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/post/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/post/01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;weekly-summary&#34;&gt;Weekly Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I focused on revising the fundamentals of business informatics and related disciplines. I dedicated time to systems analysis and explored examples of digital business transformation. In parallel, I began studying methods of working with databases, which will allow me to gain a deeper understanding of data storage and processing. For a change of pace, I visited the university library, where I found several valuable monographs on management and business process organization.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/experience/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/teaching/js/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/teaching/js/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
 is designed to give technical content creators a seamless experience. You can focus on the content and the Hugo Blox Builder which this template is built upon handles the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed videos, podcasts, code, LaTeX math, and even test students!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this page, you&amp;rsquo;ll find some examples of the types of technical content that can be rendered with Hugo Blox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teach your course by sharing videos with your students. Choose from one of the following approaches:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D2vj0WcvH5c?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Youtube&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; youtube w7Ft2ymGmfc &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bilibili&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; bilibili id=&amp;quot;BV1WV4y1r7DF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video file&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos may be added to a page by either placing them in your &lt;code&gt;assets/media/&lt;/code&gt; media library or in your 
, and then embedding them with the &lt;em&gt;video&lt;/em&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; video src=&amp;quot;my_video.mp4&amp;quot; controls=&amp;quot;yes&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;podcast&#34;&gt;Podcast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add a podcast or music to a page by placing the MP3 file in the page&amp;rsquo;s folder or the media library folder and then embedding the audio on your page with the &lt;em&gt;audio&lt;/em&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; audio src=&amp;quot;ambient-piano.mp3&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try it out:&lt;/p&gt;








  








&lt;audio controls &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;ambient-piano.mp3&#34; type=&#34;audio/mpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;test-students&#34;&gt;Test students&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide a simple yet fun self-assessment by revealing the solutions to challenges with the &lt;code&gt;spoiler&lt;/code&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; spoiler text=&amp;#34;👉 Click to view the solution&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;You found me!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; /spoiler &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;cursor-pointer&#34;&gt;👉 Click to view the solution&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;rounded-lg bg-neutral-50 dark:bg-neutral-800 p-2&#34;&gt;
    You found me 🎉
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox Builder supports a Markdown extension for $\LaTeX$ math. You can enable this feature by toggling the &lt;code&gt;math&lt;/code&gt; option in your &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To render &lt;em&gt;inline&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;block&lt;/em&gt; math, wrap your LaTeX math with &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$...${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$$...$${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;We wrap the LaTeX math in the Hugo Blox &lt;em&gt;math&lt;/em&gt; shortcode to prevent Hugo rendering our math as Markdown.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;math block&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34; data-lang=&#34;latex&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\gamma&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;_{n} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\frac&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; | &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;^T &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; |}{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\|\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{x}_{n}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{x}_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;

$$\gamma_{n} = \frac{ \left | \left (\mathbf x_{n} - \mathbf x_{n-1} \right )^T \left [\nabla F (\mathbf x_{n}) - \nabla F (\mathbf x_{n-1}) \right ] \right |}{\left \|\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n}) - \nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n-1}) \right \|^2}$$


&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;inline math&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;}}$\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n})${{&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt; renders as $\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n})$
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;multi-line math&lt;/strong&gt; using the math linebreak (&lt;code&gt;\\&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34; data-lang=&#34;latex&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;k;p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\begin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{cases}p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &amp;amp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{if }k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &amp;amp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{if }k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{cases}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt; /math &amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;


$$
f(k;p_{0}^{*}) = \begin{cases}p_{0}^{*} &amp; \text{if }k=1, \\
1-p_{0}^{*} &amp; \text{if }k=0.\end{cases}
$$



&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox Builder utilises Hugo&amp;rsquo;s Markdown extension for highlighting code syntax. The code theme can be selected in the &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```python
import pandas as pd
data = pd.read_csv(&amp;quot;data.csv&amp;quot;)
data.head()
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;pandas&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;read_csv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;data.csv&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;inline-images&#34;&gt;Inline Images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34; data-lang=&#34;go&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;icon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;python&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;inline-block  pr-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;svg style=&#34;height: 1em; transform: translateY(0.1em);&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; height=&#34;1em&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 448 512&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M439.8 200.5c-7.7-30.9-22.3-54.2-53.4-54.2h-40.1v47.4c0 36.8-31.2 67.8-66.8 67.8H172.7c-29.2 0-53.4 25-53.4 54.3v101.8c0 29 25.2 46 53.4 54.3 33.8 9.9 66.3 11.7 106.8 0 26.9-7.8 53.4-23.5 53.4-54.3v-40.7H226.2v-13.6h160.2c31.1 0 42.6-21.7 53.4-54.2 11.2-33.5 10.7-65.7 0-108.6zM286.2 404c11.1 0 20.1 9.1 20.1 20.3 0 11.3-9 20.4-20.1 20.4-11 0-20.1-9.2-20.1-20.4.1-11.3 9.1-20.3 20.1-20.3zM167.8 248.1h106.8c29.7 0 53.4-24.5 53.4-54.3V91.9c0-29-24.4-50.7-53.4-55.6-35.8-5.9-74.7-5.6-106.8.1-45.2 8-53.4 24.7-53.4 55.6v40.7h106.9v13.6h-147c-31.1 0-58.3 18.7-66.8 54.2-9.8 40.7-10.2 66.1 0 108.6 7.6 31.6 25.7 54.2 56.8 54.2H101v-48.8c0-35.3 30.5-66.4 66.8-66.4zm-6.7-142.6c-11.1 0-20.1-9.1-20.1-20.3.1-11.3 9-20.4 20.1-20.4 11 0 20.1 9.2 20.1 20.4s-9 20.3-20.1 20.3z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt; Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-helpful-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page helpful? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
