<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Markup | My Site</title>
    <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/tags/markup/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/tags/markup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Markup</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Markup</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/tags/markup/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight Markup Languages</title>
      <link>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/publication/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timursimdyanov.github.io/en/publication/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;lightweight-markup-languages&#34;&gt;Lightweight Markup Languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightweight markup languages have become a standard for preparing scientific and technical texts due to their simplicity and versatility. They allow structuring documents, adding links, tables, images, and formulas without the need for complex formats or specialized software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most widely used example is &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;, which is actively applied in academia, software development, and documentation. Its main advantage lies in the readability of the source text: even without rendering, the document remains understandable. This makes it a convenient tool both for drafting and for publishing materials online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other languages, such as &lt;strong&gt;reStructuredText&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;AsciiDoc&lt;/strong&gt;, provide extended capabilities for structuring information, making them especially useful in large projects and for preparing official documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of lightweight markup languages supports the unification of approaches to text processing, accelerates collaborative editing, and ensures integration with modern version control systems and publishing platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
